write-out-loud.com 2019-09-28

# Privacy policy- write-out-loud.com

You are here: [ HOME](https://www.write-out-loud.com/) ›  Privacy policy

I, [Susan Dugdale](https://www.write-out-loud.com/aboutme.html), the owner and operator of **write-out-loud.com**   am dedicated to protecting your data and privacy.

I recognize that your privacy is important. This document outlines the types of personal information I receive and collect when you use  **write-out-loud.com** , as well as some of the steps I take to safeguard information. This will help you make an informed decision about sharing personal information with me.

### About our cookies  

A cookie is a string of information that  **write-out-loud.com**  stores on your computer, which your browser provides to  **write-out-loud.com  **each time you return to the site. I use cookies to help me identify and track visitors, their use of my website, and their website access preferences.  

### Google analytics and Stat Counter cookies  

**write-out-loud.com**  uses Google Analytics and Stat Counter to analyze the use of this website. Google Analytics and Stat Counter collect demographic and interest data, and generate statistical and other information about website use, by means of cookies. These cookies are kept on your computer. I share this information with Google and Stat Counter, who will store and use this information on their servers. Google's privacy policy is available at: [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy\[/link). Stat Counter’s privacy policy is available at: <http://statcounter.com/about/legal/>.

**write-out-loud.com**  uses information from Google Analytics and Stat Counter to track the number of visits to the website, browsers and operating systems. No personally identifiable information is obtained from these cookies. I use the information that Google Analytics and Stat Counter generates relating to my website to create reports about the use of the site. These reports allow me to update the site and improve your usage of it.

In order to do a year to year comparison on any data collected by Google Analytics, I have set my Data Retention settings in Google Analytics to 38 months, after which Google will automatically delete the data.  

### Opt-out of data collection  

### Advertising cookies

I use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on my website. These companies use cookies and web beacons in their ads to ascertain how many times you've seen an advertisement. I share this information with these companies, but do not provide them with any personally identifiable information for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information from my website.  

You may opt out of personalized ads for over 125 different ad networks. Click the link to do that. <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>  

Some third-party advertisements are served by Google. Google's cookie enables it to serve ads to our visitors based on their visits to other sites on the Web. You may opt out of personalized ads by visiting the Google ad opt-out page here: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>  

This link from Google provides more information about how Google manages data in its ad products. Click to find out more: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>

### Affiliate products and services  

I receive an affiliate commission for some of the products/services sold on  **write-out-loud.com**.

The affiliate services platforms I use are Site Sell, ClickBank, Uncommon Knowledge (Hypnosis Downloads), and Betterhelp.  

By clicking on a product or service link, you consent to that platform's use of cookies, as outlined in the links below.

  *  **Site Sell's privacy policy:**[ https://www.sitesell.com/more-info/privacy.html](http://www.sitesell.com/more-info/privacy.html)
  *  **ClickBank's privacy policy** : <https://support.clickbank.com/hc/en-us/articles/115015510108-Privacy-Policies>
  * **Uncommon Knowledge's privacy policy** : <https://www.hypnosisdownloads.com/help-center/privacy>
  *  **Better Help's privacy policy:** <https://www.betterhelp.com/privacy/>

### Search box

The search box on this web site ("Search Box") is powered by Google Inc ("Google"). You acknowledge and agree that Google's privacy policy (located at <https://www.google.com/privacy.html>) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy.  

### Refusing cookies

You can set your browser to accept or refuse all cookies automatically, or notify you when a cookie is being requested. Taking this action should not cause a problem with the continued use of my site. Consult the Help section of your browser for guidance on how to refuse all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is requested.

If you choose to refuse write-out-loud.com's cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the site.

### Your personal information

**write-out-loud.com**  may collect and use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * To run and operate my site.
  * To display content on the site correctly.
  * To improve customer service.
  * To help me respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  * To personalize your user experience.
  * To understand how my  users as a group use the services and resources provided on our site.
  * To improve my site.
  * To improve my products and services.
  * To run a promotion, contest, survey or other site feature.
  * To send information to you that you agreed to receive about topics I think will be of interest to you.
  * To send periodic emails, which may include electronic newsletters and/or autoresponder series of emails.
  * To respond to your enquiries, questions, and/or other requests.﻿

**write-out-loud.com**  may collect personally identifiable information from you in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when you visit my site, register on the site, or fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources I make available on my site.  

If you complete a form, I will require your name and your email address, and will ask for information relevant to the purpose of the form.

For instance, if you want [speech writing help](https://www.write-out-loud.com/speech-writer.html) I will ask for information about the speech you want. If you require [coaching](https://www.write-out-loud.com/skype-coaching.html), I will want information about why and what for. If you sign up for [my newsletter](https://www.write-out-loud.com/speaking-out-loud.html) I'll need your first name and an email address to send it to, and if at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, I include unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email I send.

If you submit content to **write-out-loud.com** , I will ask for your name and email address. Photos you include with your submission, or details in your submission, may personally identify you.

If you request to be notified about comments on any content you submit to us, or request to be notified when others submit content, I will require your first name and your email address.

### Payment processor  

If you purchase a product or service from me, I will collect your name, email address, and billing address through PayPal - the payment processor I use on my site. You may review their privacy policy here: [PayPal privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en_US).  

### Anonymous use, changes & IP addresses

You can always refuse to supply personally identifiable information and visit our site anonymously. However, it may prevent you from engaging in certain site-related activities.  

If I make material changes in the collection of personally identifiable information, I will inform you by placing a notice on my site. You can be assured I will use personal information received from you for internal purposes only and will not sell it or provide it to third parties.

I also collect each visitor's IP address, which helps me combat spam and fraud. I do not use IP addresses for any other purpose.

### Social media

**write-out-loud.com** provides convenient links to our social media account on  Facebook. When you click on their links or leave a comment, your browser connects directly with that site and sends information such as your IP address, the date and time of your visit and information about how you use the social site.  

Should you wish to prevent those platforms from collecting data, please view their individual policies by using the following links:   

 **Facebook:**  to prevent Facebook from collecting data while on **write-out-loud.co** **m** , you should log out of your Facebook account before visiting our website.

I also use the social media share service AddThis which enables you, my visitors, to share pages and other resources from my website via your own social media accounts: Facebook, Twitter, Google Plus, Pinterest, Weibo, LinkedIn, or any of many others, including email.

Should you wish to prevent AddThis from collecting data, please go to their  privacy policy through the following link. It includes access to an opt-out-button.

  * AddThis [privacy policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)

### Non-personally identifiable information  

I may collect non-personally identifiable information about you whenever you interact with our site. Non-personally identifiable information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about your method of connecting to our site, such as the operating system and the Internet service provider you used, and other similar information.  

### Children's privacy protection  

This website is directed to adults. It is not directed to children under the age of 16. I operate my site in compliance with current regulations. Anyone under the age of 16 must provide parental consent to use this site. We do not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from anyone under 16 years of age.  

### Release of information

If I sell  **write-out-loud.com** , the information I have obtained from you through your voluntary participation in my site may transfer to the new owner as a part of the sale so that the service provided to you may continue. In that event, you will receive notice through my website of that change in control and practices, and I will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the purchaser honors any opt-out requests you might make.  

### Data storage

Personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information collected by this site  is stored on my host's servers. That host is SiteSell Inc., located at 1000 Saint-Jean Boulevard, Suite 702, Pointe-Claire, QC H9R 5P1 Canada.  

If you wish to review your information stored on the SiteSell servers for  **write-out-loud.com** , [click on this link](https://www.write-out-loud.com/gdpr-review.html). You can also edit, download or delete any of your information from the servers by clicking on that link.  

### How you can correct or remove information  

I provide this privacy policy as a statement to you of my commitment to protect your personally identifiable information. If you have submitted personally identifiable information through my website and would like to update that information or have it deleted from my records, [click on this link](https://www.write-out-loud.com/gdpr-request.html).

### Updates and effective date  

**write-out-loud.com  **reserves the right to make changes in this policy. If there is a material change in my cookie and privacy practices, I will indicate on my site that those practices have changed and provide a link to the updated privacy policy. I encourage you to periodically review this policy so that you will know what information I collect and how I use it.  

### Agreeing to terms  

If you do not agree to **write-out-loud.com's** privacy policy as posted here on this website, please do not consent to the setting of cookies and the collection and storage of your personally identifiable information.

Your explicit consent indicates acceptance of this privacy policy in its entirety.

 **Last updated:** 2 November 2018

You are here: [ HOME](https://www.write-out-loud.com/) ›  Privacy policy
